<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Mohan Pudasaini</title>
    <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023 Mohan Pudasaini </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/images/icon_hufd524095cdf588a6150542fb56b950be_222925_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Workshop on Data Analysis with Python</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/basic_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/basic_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Fee&lt;/strong&gt;            Rs 2000 only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;          
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/ds_basics/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  .callout {
    background-color: #f8f8f8;
    border: 6px solid #ffa500;
    margin: 1em auto;
    padding: 0.3em 10px;
    text-align: center;
    border-width: 2px;
    font-size: 1.2em;
    display: block;
    font-weight: 1000;
    animation: blink 01.5s infinite;
  }
  
  .callout.note {
    border-color: #00bfff;
  }
  
  @keyframes blink {
    0% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
    50% {
      opacity: 0.5;
    }
    100% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;callout note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VEtlBfkiUsA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;For the video of the Opening session, click here.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a critical tool for data scientists and analysts, offering a vast range of capabilities for analyzing and visualizing data. Whether you are a beginner or looking to enhance your existing skills in python, then this workshop is for you. This workshop is designed for individuals from a variety of backgrounds who have an interest in data analysis and visualization and want to learn the basics of Python programming without prior coding knowledge. The workshop is specifically targeted towards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Analysts/Data scientist:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working with different software and looking to expand their skills by learning Python for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students:&lt;/strong&gt; Interested in starting a career in data analysis or data science and want to learn the basics of data analysis using Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers and Scholars:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their thesis, research projects, or academic papers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators and Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; Who want to incorporate data analysis and visualization into their curriculum or learn Python as a tool for teaching data science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Professionals:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their work and want to learn a powerful and versatile programming language for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, you will have a solid foundation in Python programming and the ability to use Python for various data analysis and visualization tasks. With hands-on experience using Jupyter Notebook and the various libraries used in the workshop, you will be ready to tackle real-world data analysis projects.
To view the full syllabus, please 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/ds_basics/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on this opportunity to learn the most in-demand skills in the data analysis field. With a low fee, this comprehensive beginner&amp;rsquo;s workshop offers exceptional value for anyone looking to become a proficient Python data analyst. Enroll now to take your skills to the next level!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis Workshop for Health Planning Personnel</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_dhangadhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_dhangadhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Health Directorate of Sudurpashim Province organized a five-day workshop in Dhangadhi, Nepal, focused on data analysis for health planning personnel. The workshop was attended by more than 20 participants from various district health offices, who were actively involved in data management and analysis. The workshop was facilitated by Mr. Mohan Pudasaini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, participants were trained on various aspects of data analysis using R, including data cleaning and processing, statistical analysis, and data visualization. The data used for analysis was obtained from the Health Management Information System (HMIS) in Nepal, and participants were shown how to analyze the data from different perspectives related to health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants learned how to use data to identify trends and patterns, make data-driven decisions, and communicate insights effectively. The workshop provided valuable skills and knowledge to improve the quality of their data analysis and reporting, which can ultimately enhance the decision-making process in the field of health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;certificate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
