<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Mohan Pudasaini</title>
    <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 Mohan Pudasaini </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/images/icon_hufd524095cdf588a6150542fb56b950be_222925_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participated as Panelist at Paperless Trade Week 2025</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_paperless_tradeweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_paperless_tradeweek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paperless Trade Week 2025&lt;/strong&gt; was organized in Bangkok from 09–13 June 2025, jointly hosted by United Nations ESCAP, Asian Development Bank (ADB), and over 10 international organizations. This important event brought together trade experts, policymakers, and industry leaders to discuss digital trade facilitation in the evolving global context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was honored to be invited as a panelist in one of the key side events titled &lt;strong&gt;“Green Trade Facilitation and Digital Transformation”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;𝐊𝐞𝐲-𝐏𝐨𝐢𝐧𝐭𝐬-𝐟𝐫𝐨𝐦-𝐌𝐲-𝐏𝐚𝐧𝐞𝐥-𝐏𝐫𝐞𝐬𝐞𝐧𝐭𝐚𝐭𝐢𝐨𝐧&#34;&gt;𝐊𝐞𝐲 𝐏𝐨𝐢𝐧𝐭𝐬 𝐟𝐫𝐨𝐦 𝐌𝐲 𝐏𝐚𝐧𝐞𝐥 𝐏𝐫𝐞𝐬𝐞𝐧𝐭𝐚𝐭𝐢𝐨𝐧:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my panel discussion, I focused on how Artificial Intelligence (AI) can support green trade facilitation. Key points from my presentation included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong policy momentum and various global initiatives are driving the shift toward green trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expedited clearance of environmental goods is a priority for many Customs administrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The HS code system presents a challenge, as many green and non-green products share the same codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customs must maintain a balance between trade facilitation and compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI presents promising tools for identifying environmental goods and detecting potential fraud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My research developed AI models capable of classifying goods based on their commercial descriptions and flagging suspicious patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the absence of a universal definition, I used lists from three international agreements to train the models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The models demonstrated strong performance and offer practical relevance for Customs risk management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great opportunity to connect with global leaders, international agencies, trade experts, and private sector participants, and to exchange knowledge and experience.
I sincerely thank the organizers for the kind invitation and for hosting such fruitful and forward-thinking discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the program 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unescap.org/events/2025/green-trade-facilitation-and-digital-transformation-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNESCAP website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivered WCO Risk Management Workshop in Kazakhstan</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_kazakhstan_mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_kazakhstan_mission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of co-facilitating the WCO Risk Management National Workshop for the State Revenue Committee (SRC) of Kazakhstan, held at the Radisson Hotel in Astana from 12 to 14 May 2025. The workshop had 30 participants from different Customs offices of Kazakhstan Customs.
The workshop focused on various aspects of risk management such as trader categorization, insider threats, international postal stream, and interactive risk profiling dashboards. One of the most important parts was the incorporation of Artificial Intelligence (AI) approaches into Customs risk management and use cases of AI in various Customs administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop was conducted with two other WCO Risk Management Experts, Anders Alpsten from Sweden Customs and Sreya Hong of Cambodia Customs. It was a unique opportunity to collaborate, share experiences, and support Kazakhstan Customs in its journey toward more modern and resilient risk management systems. The mission was generously supported by the Customs Cooperation Fund (CCF) China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;












  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;./4.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper on Suicidal Ideation Prediction Presented at NHRC Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_nhrc_summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_nhrc_summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 11th National Summit of Health and Population Scientists in Nepal, held from 10–12 April 2025 at Soaltee Hotel, Kathmandu, I presented a co-authored research paper on 10 April.The event was organized  by Nepal Health Research Council(NHRC). Our study focused on using mobile-based Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) and machine learning to predict suicidal ideation among gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men (GBMSM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collected real-time data through smartphones to monitor mood, context, and behavior. These data were then analyzed using machine learning models to identify patterns linked to suicidal thoughts. The goal is to enable early detection and personalized mental health support for a group that faces significant stigma and mental health challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This presentation was delivered in Nepali and contributes to ongoing efforts to apply technology for inclusive, data-driven public health solutions in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentation video (57:50 to 1:08:11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  .video-container {
    position: relative;
    padding-bottom: 56.25%; /* 16:9 ratio */
    padding-top: 25px;
    height: 0;
    overflow: hidden;
  }

  .video-container iframe {
    position: absolute;
    top: 0;
    left: 0;
    width: 100%;
    height: 100%;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe 
    src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6JVTfzE8_aY?start=3470&#34; 
    title=&#34;11th NATIONAL SUMMIT OF HEALTH AND POPULATION SCIENTISTS NEPAL&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34;
    allowfullscreen
    referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;certificate.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Trade and Financial Data in Journalism at CMR Nepal - Journalism Academy</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_datajournalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_datajournalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 4, 2025, I had the privilege of leading a session on &amp;lsquo;Data Journalism&amp;rsquo; training organized by CMR Nepal - Journalism Academy. The session brought together more than 15 journalists from various media.where I discussed trade and financial data, exploring their sources, significance, and real-world applications in data-driven reporting in the context of Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made this experience particularly rewarding was the active engagement and insightful contributions from the participants. Their enthusiasm reaffirmed the pivotal role of data-driven journalism in today’s media landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for the opportunity to contribute to this important training initiative and appreciate CMR Nepal - Journalism Academy for making it possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;photo1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;group photo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Expertise: WCO Pre-Accreditation in Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_da_accreditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2025_da_accreditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to share my experience attending the World Customs Organization (WCO) First Pre-Accreditation Workshop on the area of Technical and Operational Advisers in Data Analytics, held in South Korea from January 13 to January 17, 2025. This workshop was a significant milestone in my professional journey, as it focused on evaluating various aspects of technical expertise and facilitation skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, I had the opportunity to engage in comprehensive assessments and activities designed to measure and enhance our capabilities as prospective WCO experts. I am honored to have been selected to proceed to the next stage of the accreditation process: a field mission. Successfully completing this process will enable participants to join the esteemed pool of WCO experts, collaborating with the Organization to benefit its Member states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particularly memorable moment during this workshop was the celebration of my birthday. The thoughtful gesture by the team made the occasion truly special, and I am deeply grateful to them for their kindness and support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience has not only paved the way for my continued professional growth but also strengthened my resolve to contribute meaningfully to the customs community. I look forward to the upcoming stages of the accreditation process and the opportunity to work alongside distinguished experts from around the world.
&lt;img src=&#34;photo1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Birhday celebration&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News in WCO website: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wcoomd.org/en/media/newsroom/2025/january/the-first-ever-wco-pre-accreditation-workshop-focused-on-data-analytics-holds-in-korea.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The first-ever WCO Pre-Accreditation Workshop focused on Data Analytics holds in Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Customs and Tax Practices with Data Analytics and AI</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On December 26, 2024, I had the privilege of leading a session on &amp;ldquo;Data Analytics and AI in Customs&amp;rdquo; at the Public Finance Management Training Center, Nepal. This event brought together more than 35 officials from various Customs and Tax offices, creating an enriching environment for knowledge-sharing and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the session, we delved into global trends, key World Customs Organization (WCO) initiatives, and the practical applications of data analytics and artificial intelligence within the customs. Key focus areas included risk management, fraud detection, and trade facilitation. The session also highlighted how Nepal Customs is integrating these advanced technologies into its operations to improve efficiency and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made this experience particularly fulfilling was the active engagement and insightful contributions from the participants. This exchange of ideas reaffirmed the pivotal role of data-driven approaches in shaping the future of customs and tax administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for the opportunity to contribute to this important training initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presented at the  WCO Working Group on Data and Statistics: Harnessing AI for Customs Efficiency - A BACUDA Experience</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_wgds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_wgds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was honored to present at the 5th meeting of the WCO Working Group on Data and Statistics. My presentation, titled &amp;ldquo;Harnessing AI for Customs Efficiency: A BACUDA Experience,&amp;rdquo; focused on showcasing various AI models developed as part of the BACUDA program and their applications within the customs sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the presentation, I highlighted the journey of developing AI tools, including chatbot assistance, HS classification from images, fraud detection, and automatic document processing. I shared insights into how these models are designed to streamline customs operations, enhance risk management, and improve compliance. Additionally, I discussed the deployment of AI-based systems within Nepal Customs, such as the AI-HS classification tool integrated into the Nepal National Single Window Portal, and how these initiatives reflect global trends promoted by the World Customs Organization (WCO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to present on this international platform allowed me to share our achievements, learn from fellow experts, and contribute to the broader conversation on leveraging data analytics and AI for customs efficiency. I am grateful to the WCO and the BACUDA program for facilitating this enriching experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fpudasainimohan%2Fvideos%2F860372962935775%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;314&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Analytics and AI in Customs at Public Finance Management Training Center</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 9, 2024, I had the opportunity to lead a session on &amp;ldquo;Data Analytics and AI in Customs&amp;rdquo; at the Public Finance Management Training Center in Nepal. This session was part of an in-service training program designed for gazetted third-class officers of the Ministry of Finance and their departments. It focused on providing insights into global trends, WCO initiatives, and practical applications of data analytics and artificial intelligence within the customs sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the session, we explored how data analytics and AI are revolutionizing customs operations worldwide, driving efficiency, and supporting trade facilitation. I shared information on key initiatives by the World Customs Organization (WCO) that aim to integrate these advanced technologies into customs practices. We also discussed various applications, such as risk management and fraud detection, and how these concepts are being implemented within Nepal Customs to enhance operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engaging with officers from various departments made the session especially rewarding, as it facilitated a meaningful exchange of ideas about the future of customs in a data-driven era. I appreciated the active participation and insightful discussions throughout the training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering  Research  Data  Analysis with  R</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_rworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_rworkshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Fee&lt;/strong&gt;            Rs 3000 only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;          
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/r_analysis/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;     &lt;br&gt;
          &lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;     
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/r_analysis/registration-form&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;For additional information&lt;/strong&gt;    9845074610&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  .callout {
    background-color: #f8f8f8;
    border: 6px solid #ffa500;
    margin: 1em auto;
    padding: 0.3em 10px;
    text-align: center;
    border-width: 2px;
    font-size: 1.2em;
    display: block;
    font-weight: 1000;
    animation: blink 01.5s infinite;
  }
  
  .callout.note {
    border-color: #00bfff;
  }
  
  @keyframes blink {
    0% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
    50% {
      opacity: 0.5;
    }
    100% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;!--
&lt;div class=&#34;callout note&#34;&gt;

   [For the video of the Opening session, click here.](https://youtu.be/VEtlBfkiUsA).

&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R has become an essential tool for data scientists and analysts, providing a comprehensive suite of capabilities for analyzing and visualizing data. Whether you are new to data analysis or looking to expand your skills with R, this course is tailored for you. Designed for individuals from diverse backgrounds, this course focuses on the basics of R programming, data analysis, and visualization, without requiring prior coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target Audience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Analysts/Data Scientists:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working with different software and looking to expand their skills by learning R for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students:&lt;/strong&gt; Interested in starting a career in data analysis or data science and want to learn the basics using R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers and Scholars:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their thesis, research projects, or academic papers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators and Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; Who want to incorporate data analysis and visualization into their curriculum or use R as a tool for teaching data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Professionals:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their work and want to learn a powerful and versatile programming language for data analysis.
By the end of the course, participants will have a strong foundation in R programming and the ability to perform data analysis, visualization, and statistical modeling tasks. With hands-on experience using RStudio and various R libraries covered in the course, you&amp;rsquo;ll be equipped to tackle real-world data analysis projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For registration, please 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/r_analysis/registration-form/&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss this opportunity to learn essential skills in the data analysis field. This comprehensive course offers great value for anyone looking to become proficient in R. Enroll now to elevate your data analysis capabilities to the next level!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking AI Innovations at the Auditor General&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_oag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_oag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 7, 2024, I had the honor of speaking at an event organized by the Supreme Audit Institution of Nepal,  The Office of  Auditor General&amp;rsquo;s. This event was attended by government officials from the OAG office who were keen on exploring the potential of AI in auditing processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my session, I provided an overview of artificial intelligence, tracing its timeline and highlighting the latest developments in the field. I also discussed the possible applications of AI in auditing, emphasizing the opportunities it presents for improving efficiency and accuracy in auditing processes. Additionally, I addressed the challenges and considerations that come with integrating AI technologies in such sensitive and crucial areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session was well-received, with participants engaging in discussions about the practical implications and future possibilities of leveraging AI in their work. It was a rewarding experience to contribute to the understanding and exploration of AI innovations within such a pivotal institution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Workshop on Data Analysis Using R at Quest International College</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_quest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of being invited as a resource person for the &amp;ldquo;Ultimate Workshop on Data Analysis Using R&amp;rdquo; organized by Quest International College, Nepal on June 29, 2024. This workshop focused on equipping participants with the skills needed to perform advanced data analysis using R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, I conducted a session on regression analysis, covering both linear regression and logistic regression. I explained the theoretical interrelationship between these two types of regression, how to apply these concepts using R, and the steps involved in data preparation and exploratory data analysis (EDA). Additionally, I guided participants through model development, model comparison, and the list of assumptions associated with these models. Finally, I demonstrated how to analyze and interpret the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was attended by over 30 participants, including lecturers from various colleges. It was an enriching experience, and I was delighted to share my knowledge and expertise with such an enthusiastic group of learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;photo1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Doing presentation&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;photo2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Group Photo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Workshop on Data Analysis and Machine Learning with Python</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Fee&lt;/strong&gt;            Rs 3000 only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;          
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/python_ml/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  .callout {
    background-color: #f8f8f8;
    border: 6px solid #ffa500;
    margin: 1em auto;
    padding: 0.3em 10px;
    text-align: center;
    border-width: 2px;
    font-size: 1.2em;
    display: block;
    font-weight: 1000;
    animation: blink 01.5s infinite;
  }
  
  .callout.note {
    border-color: #00bfff;
  }
  
  @keyframes blink {
    0% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
    50% {
      opacity: 0.5;
    }
    100% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;!--
&lt;div class=&#34;callout note&#34;&gt;

   [For the video of the Opening session, click here.](https://youtu.be/VEtlBfkiUsA).

&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a critical tool for data scientists and analysts, offering a vast range of capabilities for analyzing and visualizing data. Whether you are a beginner or looking to enhance your existing skills in python, then this workshop is for you. This workshop is designed for individuals from a variety of backgrounds who have an interest in data analysis and visualization and want to learn the basics of Python programming without prior coding knowledge. The workshop is specifically targeted towards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Analysts/Data scientist:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working with different software and looking to expand their skills by learning Python for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students:&lt;/strong&gt; Interested in starting a career in data analysis or data science and want to learn the basics of data analysis using Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers and Scholars:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their thesis, research projects, or academic papers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators and Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; Who want to incorporate data analysis and visualization into their curriculum or learn Python as a tool for teaching data science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Professionals:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their work and want to learn a powerful and versatile programming language for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, you will have a solid foundation in Python programming and the ability to use Python for various data analysis , visualization and machine learning tasks. With hands-on experience using Jupyter Notebook and the various libraries used in the workshop, you will be ready to tackle real-world data analysis projects.
To view the full syllabus, please 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/python_ml/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on this opportunity to learn the most in-demand skills in the data analysis field. With a low fee, this comprehensive beginner&amp;rsquo;s workshop offers exceptional value for anyone looking to become a proficient Python data analyst. Enroll now to take your skills to the next level!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WCO-UNESCAP 6th UNNExT Masterclass</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_masterclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_masterclass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to share my recent participation at the esteemed WCO-ESCAP 6th UNNExT Masterclass on &amp;ldquo;Electronic Single Windows and Data Analytics for Trade Compliance and Facilitation.&amp;rdquo; Held in Seoul, Republic of Korea from February 28th to March 8th, 2024, this event was a pivotal opportunity to contribute to the advancement of international trade practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the masterclass, I led four pivotal sessions, each offering hands-on experience and practical insights into leveraging data analytics to enhance trade compliance and facilitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Quality and Cleaning (Hands-on Session): This session provided attendees with practical exercises to address data quality issues effectively, laying a strong foundation for accurate analysis and informed decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DATE Algorithm and Risk Management (Hands-on Session): Participants actively engaged in exploring the powerful Lite DATE algorithm and its application in risk management strategies, gaining firsthand experience in utilizing data-driven approaches to enhance trade security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Language Models (LLMs): Customs Perspective (Hands-on Session): Attendees delved into the potential of cutting-edge natural language processing technologies, specifically Large Language Models, within the customs domain. Through interactive exercises, participants discovered how these models can revolutionize communication and streamline processes for greater efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Analytics: Use Cases in Nepal Customs: Bringing theory to life, I presented real-world examples of data analytics implementation in Nepal Customs operations, illustrating how data analytics can effectively enhance trade facilitation and compliance in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My engagement in the masterclass aimed to empower participants with practical skills and insights to navigate the complexities of cross-border trade effectively. By offering hands-on experience and sharing real-world examples, I endeavored to enrich the understanding and capabilities of attendees, equipping them with actionable knowledge for improved trade practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This masterclass, jointly organized by the World Customs Organization (WCO) and the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP), with the support of various esteemed organizations, attracted participants from over 20 countries across the Asia-Pacific region. Under the theme of &amp;ldquo;Electronic Single Windows and Data Analytics for Trade Compliance and Facilitation,&amp;rdquo; the event provided a comprehensive platform for knowledge exchange and skill development in the realm of international trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further details on the masterclass, please visit the UNESCAP website:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unescap.org/events/2024/wco-escap-6th-unnext-masterclass&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.unescap.org/events/2024/wco-escap-6th-unnext-masterclass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Navigating the &#34;Artificial Intelligence in Border Management&#34; Course</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2023_uvic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2023_uvic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a Customs official at Nepal Customs with a specialization in risk management, my quest for knowledge and innovation led me to an enriching experience - the course titled &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence in Border Management.&amp;rdquo; Offered by the University of Victoria (Canada) in partnership with Border in Globalization(BiG) Lab, this course promised to delve into the realm of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and its applications within the intricate landscape of border control and customs management. Over the span of four days, I was immersed in a world of insights, discussions, and hands-on learning that expanded my horizons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1: Laying the Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course commenced with a captivating session led by Thomas Cantens (World Customs organization), a brilliant mind who explored the historical and anthropological significance of customs and mathematics. This intriguing perspective shed light on how these seemingly unrelated fields have converged over time to play a pivotal role in border management. The subsequent sessions, steered by Peter Swartz(Co-founder, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://altana.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://altana.ai/&lt;/a&gt;)  introduced us to the fundamental concepts of AI and machine learning (ML). We explored the basic definitions, mechanisms, and the potential they hold for revolutionizing border control. The day continued with an exploration of knowledge graphs, offering a glimpse into how intricate network representations of the world can be leveraged for modeling trade. The practical aspect of Day 1 allowed us to apply our nascent understanding to real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2: Targeting Illicit Activities with Precision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second day was dedicated to understanding how AI and ML can be employed to target various forms of illicit activities. Peter Swartz guided us through the intricacies of employing AI to combat smuggling – whether it&amp;rsquo;s narcotics, weapons, or counterfeits. The session expanded to AI&amp;rsquo;s role in targeting revenue evasion, a critical aspect of trade regulation. The most intriguing discussions revolved around using AI for trade facilitation while maintaining the enforcement of laws and regulations. The day&amp;rsquo;s practical exercises honed our ability to devise AI-driven strategies against illicit activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3: Real-world Applications and Ethical Considerations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rim Khazall from the Canada Services and Borders Agency shared invaluable insights into the real-world applications of AI. Reflecting on practical use cases added a layer of authenticity to our learning experience. The day further delved into the deployment of AI/ML systems, tackling critical issues of privacy and security. We also grappled with the ethical dimensions of AI, exploring the defensibility and explainability of the models we were learning to create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 4: Crafting Policies for the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the course neared its conclusion, Claude Beaupres guided us through the realm of policy making, emphasizing the importance of crafting well-informed policy papers and briefs. This session bridged the technical knowledge gained throughout the course with the practical application in the real world. The day concluded with a synthesis of our learning journey through practical exercises and the opportunity to compose a paper that encapsulated our insights and learnings from the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completing the &amp;ldquo;Artificial Intelligence in Border Management&amp;rdquo; course has been an enlightening journey that has significantly enriched my perspective as a data science practitioner. This course went beyond the technical aspects of AI and delved deep into its transformative potential within the realm of border control. Not only did it equip me with a comprehensive understanding of the various AI technologies applicable in this context, but it also honed my ability to critically assess the ethical, security, and policy dimensions intrinsic to their deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Department of Energy Conducted:Nepal Border Security Workshop</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2023_radioactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2023_radioactive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States Department of Energy, National Nuclear Security Administration conducted a three-day event in Kathmandu, Nepal called &amp;ldquo;Nepal Border Security Workshop&amp;rdquo;. The event was held from March 23 to 25, 2023, and was attended by personnel from various organizations such as Nepal Customs, Nepali Army, Nepal Police, Armed Police Force, and border experts.
The primary focus of the event was on nuclear and radioactive materials detection, location, and identification. Experts from the United States demonstrated their expertise in nuclear and radioactive materials technology, various devices used for detection, location, and identification of such materials, and best practices from other countries. Scenario-based discussions were conducted to address the challenges and issues related to nuclear smuggling, detection, and deterrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Nepal Border Security Workshop&amp;rdquo; was a valuable opportunity for personnel from different organizations to come together and discuss critical issues related to border security, particularly in the detection and prevention of nuclear and radioactive materials smuggling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Workshop on Data Analysis with Python</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/basic_data_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/basic_data_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Fee&lt;/strong&gt;            Rs 2000 only&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          &lt;strong&gt;Syllabus&lt;/strong&gt;          
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/ds_basics/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
  .callout {
    background-color: #f8f8f8;
    border: 6px solid #ffa500;
    margin: 1em auto;
    padding: 0.3em 10px;
    text-align: center;
    border-width: 2px;
    font-size: 1.2em;
    display: block;
    font-weight: 1000;
    animation: blink 01.5s infinite;
  }
  
  .callout.note {
    border-color: #00bfff;
  }
  
  @keyframes blink {
    0% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
    50% {
      opacity: 0.5;
    }
    100% {
      opacity: 1;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;callout note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VEtlBfkiUsA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;For the video of the Opening session, click here.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become a critical tool for data scientists and analysts, offering a vast range of capabilities for analyzing and visualizing data. Whether you are a beginner or looking to enhance your existing skills in python, then this workshop is for you. This workshop is designed for individuals from a variety of backgrounds who have an interest in data analysis and visualization and want to learn the basics of Python programming without prior coding knowledge. The workshop is specifically targeted towards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Analysts/Data scientist:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working with different software and looking to expand their skills by learning Python for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students:&lt;/strong&gt; Interested in starting a career in data analysis or data science and want to learn the basics of data analysis using Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researchers and Scholars:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their thesis, research projects, or academic papers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators and Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; Who want to incorporate data analysis and visualization into their curriculum or learn Python as a tool for teaching data science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Professionals:&lt;/strong&gt; Who need to analyze data for their work and want to learn a powerful and versatile programming language for data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, you will have a solid foundation in Python programming and the ability to use Python for various data analysis and visualization tasks. With hands-on experience using Jupyter Notebook and the various libraries used in the workshop, you will be ready to tackle real-world data analysis projects.
To view the full syllabus, please 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/courses/ds_basics/syllabus&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on this opportunity to learn the most in-demand skills in the data analysis field. With a low fee, this comprehensive beginner&amp;rsquo;s workshop offers exceptional value for anyone looking to become a proficient Python data analyst. Enroll now to take your skills to the next level!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Writing Reproducible Research Papers with R</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mohan Pudasaini organized a 5-day virtual workshop titled &amp;ldquo;Writing Reproducible Research Papers with R&amp;rdquo; from August 25th to 29th, 2022. The workshop was designed to help students, researchers, data analysts, and teaching faculties write scientific journal papers that are reproducible and can be easily shared with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop had 45 participants from different parts of the world, who attended virtually through Zoom. The participants learned how to create dynamic documents using R markdown and how to format documents in predefined templates and their own templates in R markdown. They were also taught how to arrange titles, subtitles, and dates, manage text format and style, manage references and citations, develop tables, and more using R markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was organized by Mohan Pudasaini in his personal initiative to help researchers and students enhance their skills in writing reproducible research papers. The participants were required to have basic knowledge of R and R studio to attend the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first four days of the workshop were dedicated to teaching the participants about the different components of R markdown and how to use them. The final day of the workshop was focused on practical application, where the participants were given a sample research paper to format and finalize using the skills they had learned over the previous days.
&lt;img src=&#34;banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Department of Customs organized Workshop on Risk Management at Pokhara</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_pokhara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_pokhara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Customs (DOC), Nepal, with support from the Asian Development Bank (ADB), organized a Risk Management Workshop for customs officials of Nepal from 8 to 10 August 2022 in Pokhara, Nepal. The workshop aimed to lay the foundation for effective risk management in customs, develop risk registers and risk profiles for use in the ASYCUDA World Selectivity Module, and train customs officials in risk management to develop them into a pool of experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen customs officials from DOC and field offices participated in the training program, which covered a range of sessions. These included identifying gaps and recommended measures, sharing experiences on the development of risk management in Nepal, reviewing the risk management framework and standard operating procedures to pave the way for their effective implementation, and exploring the use of machine learning in risk management. One notable session was a presentation on &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning Approach for Customs Fraud Detection&amp;rdquo; by Mr. Mohan Pudasaini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop produced outputs such as a risk register, risk profile, and a work plan to strengthen risk management in customs. The training program was inaugurated in virtual mode by Mr. Yagya Raj Koirala and Mr. Ananda Kafle, Deputy Director Generals of DOC, and they also attended the concluding day program to provide guidance for the way forward.
&lt;img src=&#34;presentation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Workshop on Research Data Analysis Using R</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_research_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_research_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mohan Pudasaini organized a 3-week virtual workshop titled &amp;ldquo;Research Data Analysis using R&amp;rdquo; from June 25th to July 15th, 2022. The workshop covered various topics such as Introduction to R, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, Statistical Tests, Regression Analysis, ANOVA, ANCOVA, and Non-Parametric Tests. The workshop was designed to help participants, including students, researchers, data analysts, and teaching faculties, write reproducible scientific journal papers that can be easily shared with others. The workshop had 70 participants from different parts of the world who attended virtually through Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was organized by Mohan Pudasaini in his personal initiative and was spread over 21 days, with each day covering a different topic. Topics covered included data types and structure, packages in R, importing various file types, hypothesis testing, regression analysis, ANOVA, ANCOVA, non-parametric tests, and more. The workshop aimed to provide participants with a comprehensive understanding of data analysis using R and help them gain practical experience by working on examples and exercises. Overall, the workshop was a great success and helped participants enhance their skills in data analysis using R.
&lt;img src=&#34;additional.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Data Analysis Workshop at Hetauda School of Management</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_hetauda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_hetauda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 23, 2022, Hetauda School of Management, Hetauda organized a one-day workshop on &amp;ldquo;R for data analysis&amp;rdquo; with the aim to equip lecturers from Hetauda School of Management, Hetauda Campus, and Makawanpur Multiple Campus with the skills needed to use R for data manipulation, cleaning, and modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was attended by more than 30 lecturers, and Mr. Mohan Pudasaini was the trainer for the workshop. The focus of the workshop was on the practical application of R in data analysis and the lecturers were introduced to the various tools and techniques that can be used to effectively manipulate, clean and model data using R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was an excellent opportunity for the lecturers to learn and enhance their skills in data analysis, and it is expected to have a positive impact on their teaching and research in the future.
&lt;img src=&#34;additional.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis Workshop for Health Planning Personnel</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_dhangadhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2022_dhangadhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Health Directorate of Sudurpashim Province organized a five-day workshop in Dhangadhi, Nepal, focused on data analysis for health planning personnel. The workshop was attended by more than 20 participants from various district health offices, who were actively involved in data management and analysis. The workshop was facilitated by Mr. Mohan Pudasaini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, participants were trained on various aspects of data analysis using R, including data cleaning and processing, statistical analysis, and data visualization. The data used for analysis was obtained from the Health Management Information System (HMIS) in Nepal, and participants were shown how to analyze the data from different perspectives related to health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants learned how to use data to identify trends and patterns, make data-driven decisions, and communicate insights effectively. The workshop provided valuable skills and knowledge to improve the quality of their data analysis and reporting, which can ultimately enhance the decision-making process in the field of health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;certificate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Data Analysis Workshop in Mininstry of Industries Commerce and Supplies, Nepal</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2021_moics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2021_moics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Industry, Commerce and Supplies (MoICS)  organized a five-day data analysis workshop in Kathmandu, Nepal. The workshop was attended by more than 15 participants from various sections and offices under MoICS and was facilitated by Mr. Mohan Pudasaini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main focus of the workshop was trade data analysis using R, with the aim of gaining insights and values from the data. The workshop was held from July 8, 2021, to July 13, 2021.During the workshop, participants were trained on various aspects of data analysis, including data cleaning, processing, and statistical analysis. They also learned how to visualize data and use it to identify trends and patterns.I hopes that the knowledge gained from the workshop will be applied to improve trade policies and programs in Nepal. By using data to make evidence-based decisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the closing ceremony of the workshop, Joint Secretary of MoICS Mr. Prakash Dahal emphasized the importance of data analysis in the context of trade ministry and its impact on policy making. He also wished all the participants a better future, hoping that they would apply the knowledge they had gained to their work in the ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consumer Awareness Program at Gulmi</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2019_gulmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2019_gulmi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Department of Commerce, Supplies and Consumer Protection in collaboration with Consumer Forum Nepal organized a one-day Consumer Awareness Program on March 22, 2019, at Gulmi, Nepal. The objective of this program was to make consumers, business personnel, and other concerned agencies aware of their rights and responsibilities as per The Consumer Protection Act 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was presided over by Mohan Pudasaini, a representative of the Department of Commerce, Supplies, and Consumer Protection. The program was attended by various stakeholders, including representatives from government bodies, industries, and consumer groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program began with an overview of The Consumer Protection Act 2018, which is aimed at promoting and protecting the rights of consumers in Nepal. The act provides a legal framework for consumer protection and sets out the rights and obligations of both consumers and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Pudasaini emphasized the importance of consumer awareness in ensuring that consumers are able to make informed choices and protect themselves against unfair trade practices. He highlighted the various rights of consumers, such as the right to safety, right to information, right to choose, and right to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also emphasized the responsibilities of businesses and industries, including providing accurate information about their products and services, ensuring the safety of their products, and addressing consumer complaints in a timely and efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program also included a panel discussion on various consumer-related issues, such as the importance of product safety, the role of consumer protection agencies, and the need for effective complaint redressal mechanisms. The panelists included representatives from various industries, consumer groups, and government bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
