<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataAnalytics | Mohan Pudasaini</title>
    <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/dataanalytics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/dataanalytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>DataAnalytics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024 Mohan Pudasaini </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/images/icon_hufd524095cdf588a6150542fb56b950be_222925_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>DataAnalytics</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/dataanalytics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 2024 and Looking Ahead to 2025</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/summary_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/summary_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As 2024 draws to a close, I’m excited to reflect on a year filled with growth, contributions, and meaningful engagements. Alongside my regular responsibilities at Nepal Customs, I had the privilege of participating in diverse initiatives that expanded my skills, built valuable networks, and contributed to global efforts in customs and trade facilitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-achievements-in-2024&#34;&gt;Key Achievements in 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-building-networks-and-sharing-knowledge&#34;&gt;1. Building Networks and Sharing Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizing Workshops:&lt;/strong&gt; I personally organized two comprehensive 30-hour online workshops to foster a data-driven culture and strengthen networks in Nepal where I trained more than 200 participants from various sectors:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_python/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data Analysis and Machine Learning with Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_rworkshop/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Data Analysis with R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-gaining-skills-and-knowledge&#34;&gt;2. Gaining Skills and Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BACUDA Scholarship Program:&lt;/strong&gt; At the start of the year, I participated in the BACUDA Scholarship Program in Korea, where I gained invaluable insights into data analytics, artificial intelligence (AI), and their applications in customs and trade facilitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-contributing-to-wco-initiatives&#34;&gt;3. Contributing to WCO Initiatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WCO-UNESCAP 6th UNNExT Masterclass:&lt;/strong&gt; As a trainer, I shared practical tools and techniques on data quality, risk assessment, and advanced analytics with customs officials from over 20 countries.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_masterclass/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Learn more about the Masterclass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WCO Working Group on Data and Statistics:&lt;/strong&gt; I contributed to discussions on AI models and their practical applications in customs operations.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_wgds/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Details of the programme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-advancing-ai-and-data-analytics-in-nepal&#34;&gt;4. Advancing AI and Data Analytics in Nepal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting Nepal’s Supreme Audit Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuing my role as an AI and Data Analytics Specialist for the Office of the Auditor General, I have been working on various research and data analytics to enhance auditing processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading Sessions:&lt;/strong&gt; I led various sessions on AI, data analytics, and customs-related topics, contributing to professional development and capacity building:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_quest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Workshop on Data Analysis Using R at Quest International College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_oag/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI Innovations at the Office of the Auditor General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Exploring AI in Customs at the Public Finance Management Training Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pudasainimohan.com.np/talk/2024_pfmtc1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Advancing Customs Practices at the Public Finance Management Training Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has underscored the importance of leveraging data-driven approaches to drive innovation and efficiency. Engaging with global and local professionals has highlighted the value of collaboration, continuous learning, and adaptability in addressing complex challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-ahead-to-2025&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead to 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I step into 2025, my focus remains on making meaningful contributions to the customs community and advancing the ethical use of AI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributions to Customs Community:&lt;/strong&gt; Applying data analytics,  AI and risk management techniques to enhance operational efficiency and facilitate trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting WCO Initiatives:&lt;/strong&gt; Actively engaging in WCO’s global efforts to modernize customs practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advocating for Ethical AI:&lt;/strong&gt; Promoting transparency, accountability, and inclusivity in AI implementations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding Training Programs:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing workshops and courses to empower professionals with advanced skills in data analytics and AI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment to Continuous Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Embracing lifelong learning and expanding knowledge horizons to stay at the forefront of innovations in customs and trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Smarter Customs: A Data Analytics and AI Perspective</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/customs_20241123/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/customs_20241123/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Global trade has undergone a remarkable transformation in recent years. Merchandise trade volumes have steadily increased since 2015 and have been forecasted to grow in future years, showcasing the resilience of global trade systems. The sharp V-shaped recovery following the disruptions caused by COIVD 19 emphasizes how adaptable these systems have become, largely due to advancements in technology and data-driven decision-making.
&lt;img src=&#34;Picture1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Figure Source:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wto.org/english/res_e/booksp_e/trade_outlook24_e.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World Trade Organization (2024), &lt;em&gt;Global Trade Outlook and Statistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern customs authorities must adapt to the complexities of increased trade flows while ensuring efficiency, security, and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-data-challenge-in-modern-customs&#34;&gt;The Data Challenge in Modern Customs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With global e-commerce surpassing $1 trillion annually and air passenger traffic recovering rapidly, customs administrations are inundated with data from multiple sources. Effectively leveraging these data streams is critical for meeting operational demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-customs-data-sources&#34;&gt;Key Customs Data Sources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customs authorities process massive volumes of information generated across multiple domains, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Import and Export Declarations:&lt;/strong&gt; Containing detailed information about goods, parties involved, and declared values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cargo Manifests:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing logistics and carrier details critical for tracking shipments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Passenger Information (API) &amp;amp; Passenger Name Records (PNR):&lt;/strong&gt; Enabling effective risk assessment of travelers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LPCO:&lt;/strong&gt; License, Permit, Certificate, and Other Approvals,Supporting trade facilitation and regulatory compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historical Compliance Records and Enforcement Data:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhancing risk profiling and fraud detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commercial Invoices &amp;amp; Payment Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Offering transparency in financial transactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Documentation &amp;amp; Tracking Data:&lt;/strong&gt; Helping customs track goods across borders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customs operations must harness these diverse data streams to uncover actionable insights while managing the growing complexity of international trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-a-smarter-data-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Building a Smarter Data Ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As data complexity increases, the ability to store, process, and analyze data becomes a key challenge. Advanced technologies like &lt;strong&gt;data lakes&lt;/strong&gt; have emerged as a flexible solution, accommodating structured, semi-structured, and unstructured data. Data governance, security, and scalability are vital for building a reliable ecosystem to support customs operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;leveraging-advanced-analytics-and-ai&#34;&gt;Leveraging Advanced Analytics and AI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced analytics and artificial intelligence (AI) are transforming customs operations, offering:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time Risk Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt; AI-powered risk scoring systems for fraud detection and predictive analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Document Processing:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools like OCR and natural language processing (NLP) for faster, more accurate trade document reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation and Classification:&lt;/strong&gt; Automated HS code classification and verification systems using machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Audit Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Risk-based audit selection and compliance monitoring using data analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;leading-innovations-by-the-world-customs-organization-wco&#34;&gt;Leading Innovations by the World Customs Organization (WCO)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WCO is at the forefront of technological adoption in customs. Key initiatives include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Powered HS Classification Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Automating the classification of goods for customs duties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fraud Detection Models (DATE):&lt;/strong&gt; Identifying patterns and anomalies in trade data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced X-Ray Image Analysis:&lt;/strong&gt; Using AI for accurate detection of contraband in cargo inspections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Customs Projects:&lt;/strong&gt; Addressing member countries&amp;rsquo; technological challenges through innovative solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-path-forward&#34;&gt;The Path Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intelligent integration of these technologies will shape the future of customs management. For successful implementation, customs administrations need to focus on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robust Data Strategies:&lt;/strong&gt; Including standardization, secure sharing protocols, and governance frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Scalable systems that are secure and user-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workforce Development:&lt;/strong&gt; Upskilling staff in analytical techniques, AI tools, and data management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformation of customs through data analytics and AI is not just a response to the increasing complexity of trade but a proactive step toward building smarter, more adaptive systems. These advancements will enable customs administrations to streamline processes, enhance security, and maintain compliance.
As global commerce continues to evolve, customs administrations must remain at the forefront of innovation. The ability to harness emerging technologies and leverage diverse data sources will be the cornerstone of efficient and effective border management in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
