<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WCO | Mohan Pudasaini</title>
    <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/wco/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/wco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>WCO</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025 Mohan Pudasaini </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/images/icon_hufd524095cdf588a6150542fb56b950be_222925_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>WCO</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/tag/wco/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Becoming a WCO Accredited Risk Management Expert</title>
      <link>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/2025_accreditation_journy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pudasainimohan.com.np/post/2025_accreditation_journy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Achieving WCO accreditation was a dream I had since the day I first heard about it after joining Nepal Customs. In 2025, that dream finally came true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-classroom-to-customs&#34;&gt;From Classroom to Customs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My professional journey began in education. After completing Grade 12, I started teaching tuition classes and later joined a private school as a teacher. Those early years shaped my values of hard work, discipline, and dedication. Teaching also sparked my passion for facilitation, which would become a central part of my Customs career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-chapter-joining-nepal-customs&#34;&gt;A New Chapter: Joining Nepal Customs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the Civil Service in 2014. In 2017, I started working with Nepal Customs. It was during one of my first WCO-supported national workshops that I first heard the term “WCO Accredited Expert”. As the facilitator introduced himself, I felt an instant connection to that role. It blended my passion for training with technical expertise. I vividly remember going home that evening and searching online to learn everything I could about the accreditation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vision-with-action&#34;&gt;A Vision with Action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered that one of the main eligibility criteria was minimum five years of experience in Customs. I set my sights on that goal and took action. I began reading the WCO website regularly, studying updated materials, tools, and instruments. At the same time, I worked hard to sharpen my data analytics skills. Alongside my regular duties, I continued facilitating internal trainings and workshops. My background in teaching gave me the confidence and ability to connect with participants and make complex ideas simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this period, I was also honored with several awards including Best Teacher and Best Employee, which reinforced my motivation to keep pushing forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;awards_photo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Collage showing Best Teacher, Best Employee, and Customs Recognition Awards – WCO accredited expert and trainer from Nepal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-road-to-accreditation&#34;&gt;The Road to Accreditation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2022, I noticed that WCO had circulated letter for a Pre-Accreditation Workshop on Risk Management. I applied through my administration and was nominated by Nepal Customs. I was fortunate to be shortlisted among 12 candidates from the Asia-Pacific region. It was one of the happiest and proudest moments of my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2022, I participated in the pre-accreditation workshop held in Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;RM_Accreditation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Participating in WCO Pre-Accreditation Workshop on Risk Management – Customs and data analytics expert from Nepal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was intense and challenging. Each day involved new assignments, presentations, group exercises, and report writing. I was often sleeping only 3 to 4 hours due to the pressure to perform. But I stayed focused and succeeded in passing this stage of the accreditation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;accreditation-achieved&#34;&gt;Accreditation Achieved&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued building my skills and staying current with global Customs developments. Then in 2025, I received an invitation for the final mission for  accreditation. I successfully conducted the mission and officially certified as a &lt;strong&gt;WCO Accredited Technical and Operational Advisor on Risk Management&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Official Certificate of WCO Accredited Technical and Operational Advisor on Risk Management – Customs expert and facilitator&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-commitment-ahead&#34;&gt;My Commitment Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This accreditation is not the end. It is the beginning of a larger responsibility. As a WCO accredited expert, I am committed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitating national and international capacity building programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting WCO members to enhance their risk management systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting the use of data analytics in Customs for trade facilitation and risk management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to global Customs modernization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
